嗯,稍等一下哦。
好。
看来大家对胡桃夹子没有什么问题嘛。
那我们就来回顾一下今年的直播哈。
对于刚关注我们MD官方bilibili这个账号的小伙伴们,
今年的话呢,我们是做了几次直播的。
第一次直播呢,就是个蒸汽捧客风格的HANA的套装。
这一期呢,是我们的一年一度的用户交流大会。
我们的用户交流大会一般是办在年末或者是年初,第二年的年初。
这个是我们今年年初的,是邀请了Substance的那个Chino作为我们的嘉宾,还有强哥。
那一期的话,很推荐大家去观看,因为那一期的话,那一期我们嘉宾还是很给力的。
然后这个是我那一期做的一套风格。
其实还挺简单的,就是看上去好像很复杂。
其实这个裙子的你可以看到,这个裙子的质板啊,这些都是很简单的质板。
然后也是直接用板片这样去缝和固定的。
那像我们之前,也是的,像我做纽扣的话呢,我通常都是用粉纤线做固定。
然后这个纽扣就是适合装饰这样。
好。
然后这个就是第一期真气捧舞课。
接着是第二期,第二期是做帽子。
当时我们做了很多款帽子。
包括像这个魔术帽啊,牛仔帽,还有包括像这种贝雷帽的打扮。
还有这个棒球帽。
还有中间是一个简单的把帽子变形。
做成一个。
嗯,小朋友,小朋友会戴的这种遮仰帽。
啊,或者女士的遮仰帽这样。
这是第二期。
对帽子感兴趣的小伙伴可以回头看一下那一期。
啊,帽子这一期。
帽子这一期应该也是有请嘉宾的。
嗯,帽子这一期的嘉宾应该是老N。
对的。
对吗?
对的,对的,对吗?
对的,对的,对的。
因为我有点想不起来,中间,中间应该还是有,还有一期请过嘉宾。
我记得Annie Ryden今年也来过。
哦,西装,是不是西装这一期?
哦,对,Annie Ryden是,是做半身裙。
哎呀,半身裙的这个,这个素材我找不着了。
对,中间还有一期是讲半身裙。
半身裙因为我做了很多款半身裙。
所以说大家感兴趣的话可以看一下我们就是这一期。
就我后续又出了一个比较详细解释版本的这个制作半身裙。
啊,这一期的话大家也可以去看一下。
因为制作半身裙的话还是,嗯。
就比较实用的。
哦,那我直接看这里的吧。
接下去一期是这个,做鞋子的。
哦,做鞋子的这个项目文件可以给大家开开来看一下。
这个就是刚才有小伙伴问说在MD当中能不能做靴子嘛,也是可以的。
啊,我之前是在MD当中做了这样一双靴子。
你可以看到它的那个,哦,像我这种结构都是用版片去做的。
哦,然后包括我们的鞋带啊,还有,嗯,还有这一些效果啊,都是版片打的。
那一期的话大家也可以去看一下。
做靴子的这一部分我还是做的比较仔细的。
然后也有教大家怎么样一点一点去打这个板。
哦,然后那一期还做了一个制服鞋。
制服鞋是长这样的。
哦,制服鞋。
其实鞋子的话就是打好基础,就是做好这个鞋子的底板是最重要的。
哦,我还给它加了双丝袜。
好吧。
然后,哦,做丝袜的话在,在有一年的这个圣诞节当中我们有讲过怎么做丝袜。
然后兔女郎当中好像也讲过怎么做丝袜。
兔女郎讲没讲,好像是在这,在这一期圣诞节是肯定讲过怎么做丝袜的。
诶,是不是这一期?
对,是这一期。
铁定讲过怎么做丝袜。
嗯,所以如果对做丝袜感兴趣的话可以去看那一期。
然后是沙发。
嗯,沙发这个的话,这一期的话就可能有,就比较有难度吧。
所以,嗯,看的小伙伴就比较少。
嗯,平时做家居装潢啊这一方面的话可以看一下做沙发的这一期。
其实做沙发也是比较重要的部分。
其实难点都不是在怎么做这样的蓬松的效果。
难点是在于怎么把这个侧面的这一些包边给包好。
哦,像做这种,这种效果其实你加一个压力,然后给一些,嗯,弹性去收紧它这个位置。
然后改一下物理属性就可以了。
这个是沙发那一期。
嗯,沙发的话。
这个沙发是有上传到connect,就是我们的那个商城里面的。
商城里面是有的。
再之后就是牛仔了。
牛仔这一期。
嗯,哦,中间还有一期。
中间还有一期那个,嗯,做西装的那一期。
对,这个是牛仔。
牛仔的话就是有风衣嘛。
这个是比较,嗯,比较强。
然后那个的风衣。
然后也有这个围巾,怎么打的。
这个围巾也是做比较简单的一个围巾嘛。
围巾,然后,然后马甲,还有里面的衬衫。
但是衬衫是做了一个卷袖子的。
然后包括外面的风衣。
好,感兴趣的小伙伴可以看一下,好像还用了一点吹风嘛。
用了一点吹风。
给美根压力啊,美根。
用了一些吹风脚。
嗯,牛仔服好像也上传到商城了。
就是还蛮多我们直播的东西会上传到商城的。
然后之后就是这一套。
这一套的话就是,嗯,这个,这个,这一套衣服做的起因是因为当时我在微博上面有看到有一个小伙伴说。
他不知道怎么在MD当中去翻折这样子多层的衣服。
所以说当时我就,正好是因为,嗯,平时大家问怎么做这个羽绒服的小伙伴也比较多嘛。
然后包括,包括有小伙伴会问说我怎么拿这个衣服去做绑结,在腰部做这样子的绑结,尤其是像这种多层次的衣服。
嗯,所以说当时就是开了这样的一个。
嗯。
直播。
所以如果对做多层次衣服,你看啊,这个衣服它就有很多层,一层,两层,三层。
嗯?怎么只有三层?
嗯?
我以为我做了四五层呢。
好吧。
三层的衣服,然后包括像这样袖子也是有两层,很多层去做绑结的。
这样。
嗯,试直播啊。
试直播。
好吧。
哈喽。
你好,GCMU,你好。
啊,对,就是给压力。
然后内部线的话,不是啊,内部线没有折叠,因为内部线会有分线。
啊,你看啊,比如说我找一个那个,嗯,找一个,诶?
啊?
哦,等一下啊。
比如我们找一个模型。
就是做羽绒服其实很简单。
羽绒服很多时候,嗯,就是只是做一个加一件衣服。
然后我们在上面加一些内部线。
好。
就比如说,加一些内部线。
因为在克隆层的时候,内部线之间会自动创建分线。
对齐到半分半线。
啊。
这个我们内部线创建好了之后,直接给它克隆层,克隆到外部。
好。
然后模拟。
模拟好了之后,外层给它加一些弹性,呃,不是,给它加一些压力。
然后内层因为要平衡。
然后压力是要平衡的。
对吗?
我们的压力啊,正面朝外。
看一下正面啊。
压力。
压力的时候是正面朝外垂。
啊。
那我要它,让它压力平衡。
那这边也是要正面朝,就是正面朝里垂。
啊。
绑刀外线是什么?
就是画,对,画内部线,然后把它延伸到板片外线上。
之后它那个内部线就会自动安排好嘛。
然后你再给它一点压力。
然后因为我们在克隆层的时候。
啊。
我再给大家看一遍啊。
我们克隆层。
好。
现在是有了板片,对不对?
啊。
有了板片之后,克隆层,克隆到外部的时候,所有已经在这个板片上面的内部线之间,都会自动去创建缝纫线。
那在这样有缝纫线和缝纫线,就是有内部线和内部线缝纫的这样子的一个约束下。
我们给内外板片用相反方向的压力。
嗯?
哦。
用对齐到板片外线上。
这样啊。
我们选择一头或者说一整根内部线,右键有个对齐到板片外线。
啊。
这样就会对齐。
如果你选一整根线的话,那就是整根线对齐到板片外线上。
好。
那如果是交叉的内部线的话。
啊。
比如说这个点你可以选择对齐到内部线,它会自动切到这一边来。
这是对齐功能。
嗯嗯。
好。
那我们在克隆层出来之后,这个板片,因为我们有了压力,然后中间这边的凹陷只是因为缝纫线和缝纫线缝到了一起去,所以它才会有凹陷。
再加上我们有这个压力的充值。
啊。
它就会变得跟羽绒服一样。
明白吗?
然后再说一遍啊,压力是要这个平衡的,如果不平衡的话是会飞出去的,板片。
好。
嗯。
这个就是我们的多层服装,然后最后的话就是今天的嗯,胡桃夹子。
啊。
胡桃夹子的话,这一个项目文件是有上传到我们的。
嗯。
官方商城上面的,所以大家感兴趣的话可以去下载一下。
官方商城的地址在,嗯,在这个视频的开头,有跟大家讲到哈。
就是这个地址。
connect.coo-set.com, connect。
诶,在这里。
会不会被挡着啊?
哦,没有被挡着,刚好。
在这个地址上面可以去下载啊,在全部里面搜一下。
然后找到我们MD官方就可以了。
好。
大家平时用MD有什么问题吗?
做多层的时候布料会一直抖动啊。
嗯。
这是一个很宽泛的问题。
你用的是GPU模拟吗?是CPU模拟吗?
像这种抖动的问题的话,最好是加群然后发一下视频,给我看一下。
给尼龙羽绒布料的时候啊,你要看粉刃线有没有穿层粉刃。
就是什么叫做穿层粉刃啊,就是想到讲一句啊。
嗯,这是第一层。
好。
我们在它上面画一根线。
然后。
然后这是一层。
这是两层。
这是三层。
如果你的粉刃线越层粉刃了。
比如说这两个板片缝到一起,OK,没问题,是稳定的。
然后你再把这个板片和第一层缝到一起。
看到没有,它就会不稳定。
越层粉刃会不稳定。
不会容易发生这个问题。
好。
还有一种情况。
嗯,你看这样缝的话它就是稳定的。
所以不要越层去粉刃。
这个是第一点。
第二点,你用尼龙的时候不稳定。
我觉得你最好还是,嗯,可以加群,然后翻到群里面看一下你那个布料的问题。
因为我平时做布料就很少遇到不稳定的问题。
我觉得可能跟个人操作习惯有关系。
或者你,我想一下,或者你有没有在穿插的时候。
哦,我知道了。
我知道了,你的粉刃线类型是不是没有设置为turn的。
这样也会引起不稳定的。
就是板片和板片叠起来的时候。
因为内部线上的粉刃线只能设定为turn的。
但是侧边的粉刃线,你看。
哦,他们就是会可以设置为custom mango,或者说可以设置为turn的。
嗯?嗯?
为什么这个板片自己开始不稳定了起来。
那就把它的粒子间距降低一点。
这样。
我觉得尤其是像这种很多情况下很复杂的情况而导致的这种。
因为多层的服装它整体环境肯定就是一个很复杂的环境嘛。
像这种情况下你最好在群里面发一下你的视频。
然后我再提一下哦,大家如果你加了微信。
不是,如果你加了QQ群的话。
哦。
你加了QQ群的话呢。
是截图的时候啊。
是因为我的QQ群名字就要问问题配截图嘛。
配截图不要配这样的截图。
这样我很难理解。
就是配截图的时候一个是尽量清晰。
就是比较宽大一点。
能够让我看到全貌。
然后你可以重点标注一下哦,不稳定的是这里或者是不稳定的是这里。
就给我看到你的这个2D3D的界面。
包括属性编辑器。
还有地面网格也可以让我看一下。
有的时候大家那个导家那个模型啊比例太小了。
然后按照那个很小的比例做衣服就说这个衣服做上去怎么没细节。
很多时候就是因为用的就是用的模型比例太小了。
什么版本?
是Marvelous Designer 12。
Marvelous Designer 12最新版。
因为我们软件现在已经更新到MD12了嘛。
今天主要还是想跟大家讲一下就是动画编辑器当中还是可以帮助大家解决很大一部分问题的。
嗯。
然后。
大家平时还有什么问题吗?
用MD的问题。
嗯?
In fact, it is already more suitable for a lot of situations, but there is still a lack of places.
Yes, Chengdu will be added. Everyone always says that Chengdu has to loosen the grid.
How much is this version? Hey, little buddy, you asked the point.
No. 31 is coming to an end. Recently, we are doing an event with 12 individual versions of Marvelous Designs.
The year of the package is 1,400, because the original price is 70%. The original price is 2016 a year, and the price is 70%.
If you are interested, you can go to our official website and have a look, because we are doing this black dance event recently.
In fact, everyone always says that our software is expensive.
But our software, our software, you average down to a month, in fact, it's really okay.
You usually buy an iQiyi, you have to go to any random TV-watching website, you have to pay 20-30 yuan a year.
Right? Our software also has so many customer support services, and these tutorials, videos, these, right?
Yes.
Of course, you are also welcome to add our QQ group at any time.
You can speak more and chat more in the group.
I hope everyone takes care of their health.
The scene of the animation version application?
The animation version application, this is actually mainly up to you.
If you need to do some animation materials for your work,
then you definitely need to use an animation editor.
But if you are just a person who usually does mirroring,
then it doesn't matter.
It's not very important.
Unless you are doing animation with a wind controller,
that is, you want your clothes to float up,
but you feel that using a wind controller directly,
it can't capture the effect you want,
then you just start recording an animation to record a wind blowing,
and then it's stuck in the middle.
It's paused under a needle.
The latest basic tutorial?
Actually, it depends on the basic tutorial of the previous version.
The new version and the old version have no difference in core functions.
The usage is still the same.
On our official website,
you can see a newbie entry.
This episode of the newbie entry is enough.
This episode of the newbie entry has subtitles,
so you don't have to watch the voice.
Because a friend of mine said that
I saw other people doing other tutorials,
and they said that
Marvelous Designer's official dubbing is very
I didn't think so.
Actually, I'm fine.
Maybe when I recorded the video before,
the dubbing was less passionate.
Because this video was made before.
Now it's not.
Now it should be quite positive.
Let's look at this quick tutorial first.
In fact, in our dynamic column,
there is that
I am a little star.
In the second episode,
Is there any recommended tutorial?
If you are a pure star,
please watch the quick entry.
After you have the concept,
you are welcome to learn the 10-minute series of videos.
After that,
this is simple.
You can follow it.
You can watch video 1, video 2, video 3.
These points are all there.
OK.
Let's continue to update this column.
There are a lot of videos
in this column.
If there is any thing
that you are interested in
in terms of how to make a video,
please watch the first half of the video.
And then we will make the video 3.
So let's continue.
Thank you very much.
See you next time.
Bye-bye.
Have a nice day.
See you next time.
This is actually quite convenient, because you can link to those videos.
But it seems like everyone doesn't really look at the magazine.
So I will keep reminding everyone to look at the magazine.
There are many ways to solve problems in the magazine.
Do you still have any questions?
Welcome to join our QQ group.
Our QQ group often has a lot of people.
You can send us a private message, and we will look at the three groups.
We will look at which group has an empty spot, and then we can join the group.
Actually, our live broadcasts are all...
Basically, I will reply to everyone's questions.
So you can pay attention to our Bilibili account,
and see if there are any live broadcasts.
These are the previews for live broadcasts.
You can come and watch the live broadcasts.
Of course, you can also join our QQ group.
Of course, if I have time during work, I will reply to the messages.
Even if I don't see it,
I will say that I haven't had the chance to reply to the QQ group yet.
There are also more enthusiastic friends who will reply.
I hope everyone can be healthy in the new year.
Don't work too hard.
Of course, this is the last live broadcast of 2022.
You won't...
This has been summarized at the end of the year.
I have done some things this year.
What direction is the development direction for next year?
There may be a second one.
What is the second one about?
What is it about?
You can also leave us a message about what you usually want to see.
If I see it, I will reply to you.
MD...
MD joined...
Will it be very difficult to enter the door?
No.
We are fine.
I have always felt that it is not very difficult for us to enter the room.
Because...
Because if you really can't do it, you can directly use the ready-made clothes.
You can use the ready-made clothes to get down.
You...
It's actually very fast to enter the door.
It's relatively...
It takes some time to do it.
It's a bit true.
It's a year old and it's so fast.
Yes.
This is a year old.
I think it's really super fast this year.
I always feel that one year has passed.
How to make a skirt?
Look at this women's clothing.
I think this is about the same as a skirt.
This is what I think.
You can take a look at this episode of women's fashion.
I actually recommend everyone to watch this episode of women's fashion, because I talked very carefully about it this time.
And I think children will understand and learn from it.
收縮扣?收縮扣是什麼?收縮扣是什麼?
我在反覆的在問,是像皮帶那種嗎?還是那種?
為什麼圍裙會有收縮扣啊?
等一下,我去搜一下。
淘寶說,
收縮扣?收縮扣?
等一下,
伸縮扣?伸縮扣?
那種的話,就是會把那種扣子以虛擬模特形式擋住。
把那種扣子以虛擬模特形式擋住。
然後把布料掛在上面。
但是如果你要做這個圍裙的動畫,要不呢你就得給這個扣子做K針,就是做動畫。
要不呢你只能以這個復健的形式擋進來,然後把它貼附到一個透明的看不到的版片上面。
然後去做,做這個扣子。
做這個動畫叫做雙層布料。
做雙層布料,有啥技巧或者注意事項嗎?
做雙層布料就像我之前有講到過的,你在克隆層之前先把那個衝突厚度提高,然後讓它膨起來有空間。
做雙層布料有啥技巧或者注意事項嗎?
之後再用,再把它的衝突厚度降低,不要模擬,然後直接克隆層。
Then reduce the conflict thickness, don't simulate it, and then directly make double layers in the column layer.
Also, if you are manually sewing the inner and outer layers, remember to set the sewing line of the edge as Turn.
Another thing to note is not to sew very soft fabrics and very hard fabrics together.
For example, if one of the fabrics is Turn, and the other one is
the hem, then don't sew them together.
Because if you sew them together,
the fabric will not be stable because of the difference in properties.
Time really flies so fast.
A year has passed like this.
For example, let's use a harder fabric for this one.
Canvas.
A fabric like this.
Oh, forget it. Let's use a harder one for this one.
This one is called Rigid.
And then,
let's use a very soft fabric for the bottom one.
So comfortable.
Look.
It will be very strange and funny when it's here.
That's it.
Shorter fabric.
I guess the Shorter fabric I'm talking about is...
is...
is the one I just mentioned.
Like a gluten.
I really love to eat a baked gluten.
Is there anyone who doesn't like to eat a fragrant baked gluten?
I think the most favorite thing I eat in college
is the baked gluten.
Not the baked, the fried gluten.
I love to eat the baked one as well.
I also like to eat the fried one.
When sewing,
No no no no!
When I was working at DoubleStand
There were times when the visual cards were...
Let me see
Now I have a layer of clothing
There is a little distance between the model and the clothing
Forget it, I'll show you
Ah, I know! Adjustment button, that's what I was talking about, you just need to change it to virtual model
Which episode did I talk about this before?
I think it's the episode of the assassin
It's probably the episode of the bandit
Or maybe it's the episode of the collaboration with Substance
For example, this version is single-layer
And then you clone it to the other side
And it will have some overlap
Of course it's okay if it's stable now
Sometimes the folded fabric
If it's not stable, you can make the conflict thickness very high
Of course don't make it that high
For example, 5
And then, if the next step is good, then it's okay
Don't model it anymore
You can make the conflict thickness lower to 1
And then you clone it
For example, here we choose to clone it to the outside
And then you model it
It's stable
It will be stable after a while
But when you clone it, you have to pay attention
Like this
Folding position
It's best not to let it
There's a seam line
Look, this side is over
It's over the board
It's easy to be unstable
And there's a seam line in the middle
Delete this extra seam line
Don't let it affect your double-layer structure
But in fact, this
What to use
This conflict thickness
Still
Less
You can take a look at the last live broadcast
Well
This live broadcast
This live broadcast has a reward
Why is there a reward?
Why do you make this kind of multi-layer clothes?
It's more troublesome
Oh, this issue also invited guest Juefei
The part of Juefei's speech is particularly detailed and particularly good
And then
Well
Do multi-layer
It's the same when doing this side of the knot
I made a knot on the first layer
Then use
Uh, shell
Then use the conflict thickness to push it away
Yes
Make
Make enough thick
This air
Keep it in the middle
Then grow in the cologne layer
Um
Ah
Anyway, you can watch this video
Do multi-layer clothes
At this time
Um
Do you have any questions?
But it's Christmas tomorrow
Yes, you can
You can usually take a look at our previous ones
This one
The main thing is that you can actually look at the dynamic first
You can look at it because every time I do it before the live broadcast
I will post that
Dynamic and then in the dynamic
There will be such a
The overall effect of the clothes
You can take a look
Will it include the one you want in the middle?
That kind of
For example, like this multi-layer clothes
Ah
I turned off the Internet again
But like this
content
If there is no problem
Then we may have to end here today
If everyone is interested
You can follow us
Bilibili account MD official
And join our
This fan group
Not a fan group
Um
MD user communication group
Ah
Thank you very much
Okay
Thank you all
Oh
I know
ZESR Quadro
Oh
I said your ID is so familiar
Did you win the award at the user exchange conference last year?
How to be a hand-in-hand agent
I talked about it in the episode of Little Wife Hannah
Um
Oh
It's Little Wife Hannah
You go search
Our official
Official
You search for Little Wife Hannah
Little Wife Hannah
Then you will see that episode
You can know how to do hand-in-hand
In fact, it's
It's just that you put that
Let me take a look at my computer
Is there that posture?
You just take that board
Just pull it out
You just take out the pocket board
Just take out the pocket board
Just assume
Let's pretend that there is a pocket board here
Just a piece of clothing
Then you put
Ah
No
I have to
I have to find a piece of clothing
Let me show you
Show you
I do this
I put
I left
I stick
I put
I hold
I make
I stick
And then
This plank
Pull over
Then freeze it
Let's freeze it first, then turn on the fire.
But the way I'm doing it is quite special.
Normally, you wouldn't make this weird structure.
Just move it over, and then it's done.
Because it has a lot of grid on the back of the hand,
the grid is too small when you have a bigger one,
and if you can't wrap it, you can just reduce the number of particles.
Okay?
Do you understand?
If you can't wear it on the back of the hand, you can adjust it a little bit.
It depends on which hand you're using.
If your hand is flat, you won't have this problem.
Okay.
It's okay.
That's all for today.
Welcome to follow our official Bilibili account,
and our WeChat account, Marvelous Designer.
I hope you have a healthy new year.
See you next time.
Bye-bye.